LINDA DI FEDERICO

Toronto, ON M4V 1C4

Phone: 647.521.9728 | Email: difedericolinda@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/linda-maria-di-federico/ | GitHub: github.com/ldifederico/ | Portfolio: ldifederico.github.io/Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with training in Science and Mathematics. An innovative character allowed successful publication of two scientific papers that joint statistics, algebra and computing to further research in the field of environmental science. Recognized by peers for hardworking nature, unique outlook and good-humored attitude.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, JSON

Databases: MySQL, MongoDB

Other: Heroku, Git, Microsoft Office Suite, ArcGIS, Grapher

PROJECTS

coleague | github.com/ldifederico/Fantasy-League/ | coleagueapp.herokuapp.com/

A full-stack web application that promotes teambuilding within companies by combining the friendly competition instilled within football fantasy leagues and the excitement of sports betting. My core responsibilities included UX/UI design and other aspects of the front-end development. Tools used: HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap 4.3.1, API-Football, MySQL

EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Ontario's Ministry of the Environment and Climate Change

June 2017 – August 2018

Toronto, ON

Collaborated with academic and federal institutions to compile a near-road air monitoring report. Simultaneously coauthored a manuscript discussing the concentrations of metals in the air in the near-road environment at varying locations across the Greater Toronto Hamilton Area. Presented research to large audiences from diverse fields.

Research Assistant May 2016 – June 2017

Ontario's Ministry of the Environment and Climate Change

Toronto, ON

Completed the chapter on ozone trends in Canada and the United States for the 2016 Air Quality Report, wrote a proposal for the federal government advising reconsideration of the current particulate matter standards, and authored a paper on the dispersion of ultrafine particulate matter in the near-road environment.

Volunteer Coordinator Kingston General Hospital

September 2013 – April 2017

Kingston, ON

Aided the Pediatric Unit and Mental Health Unit by partaking in patient care and facility maintenance. Led introductory and training sessions to new-coming volunteers. Awarded the Kingston General Hospital Student Bursary.

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development University of Toronto

September 2019 – December 2019

Toronto, ON

A full-time intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express & ReactJS.

School of Continuing Studies Queen's University

September 2018 - August 2019

Kingston, ON

Returned to Queen's to take additional courses in mathematics and spanish.

Bachelor of Science (Honours) in Environmental Sciences

September 2013 - April 2017 Kingston, ON

Queen's University Kingston, ON Awarded a Queen's Excellence Scholarship and was acknowledged as a Dean's Scholar for academic excellence.